ROUTE 52, LAKE INAGAKO BROAD AREA AGRICULTURE LINE WESTERN LINE
(國道52號 伊奈湖) (廣域農道 西部道路)
LAID-BACK CAMP SEASON 3
《搖曳露營△ (第三季)》
EPISODE 10: CHIKUWA, TRAM AND CHIAKI SOLO CAMPING
(第10話 竹輪和電車和千明的單人露營)
EAST MOUNT KAYAGATAKE BROAD AREA AGRICULTURE LINE
(茅之岳東部廣域農道)
YAGIHAKO PARK
(八木羽湖公園)
It feels nice to drive on the route
那位姊姊告訴我的路線
Sakura told me about.
超好跑的耶
Let's see.
我看看喔
I came from the Western Line
剛才是從西部道路
and passed through the Mount Kayagatake Broad Area Agriculture Line.
經過茅之岳東農道過來的
I should take the Shosen Green Line next.
接下來就要走昇仙峽綠色道路了呢
There are so many cats around this lake.
總覺得這座湖邊有好多貓喔
I knew it. It's easier with dogs.
果然還是狗比較好
Here's your vegetable soup, Sakura.
來 這是蔬菜湯喔 姊姊
Thank you.
謝謝
It's a nice day to admire the cherry blossoms.
真是個賞櫻的好天氣呢
Agreed.
對呀
The sunshine is so warm and cosy.
而且陽光暖烘烘的 很溫暖
Looks like it's going to start raining next week.
下禮拜好像就會開始下雨
This could be the last chance to see the cherry blossoms this year.
這大概是今年最後一次賞櫻了吧
I'm glad we came out while the sun was still out.
幸好有趁天氣晴朗時 出來逛逛呢
We started having cherry blossom drives
這個賞櫻兜風
after you got your driving license.
是從姊姊考到駕照後開始的
This year marks...
所以今年是…
The third time.
第三次喔
Yeah!
沒錯…
It'll be great to come see
要是以後也能像這樣
the cherry blossoms every year.
每年一起來賞櫻就好了
You're going to college. Who can say for sure?
畢竟妳還要升學 以後的事情誰說得准呢
You have a point.
說得也是呢
What do you plan to do after graduating?
姊姊大學畢業後要做什麼呢?
Well...
這個嘛
"NADESHIKO" Going cherry blossom viewing with Sakura.
(撫子) 我接下來要跟姊姊去賞櫻巡禮
Rin is solo-camping.
凜自己去露營
Nadeshiko and her sister are viewing cherry blossoms.
撫子跟姊姊去賞櫻啊
Let's get going, Chikuwa.
那我們也出發吧 竹輪
Chikuwa, look over here!
竹輪 看我這邊
Hyah.
嘿咻
Such a pleasant day.
天氣真好
Today might be perfect for camping.
今天或許很適合露營呢
What's wrong?
怎麼了嗎
Oh my, do you like that bag?
怎麼 你喜歡那個包包嗎
You really do like squeezing into narrow spaces.
真是的 你就喜歡待在狹窄的地方
Such a good dog.
摸摸…
Was that too much?
摸得太過頭了嗎
The whole place is full of cherry blossoms!
滿滿都是櫻花啊
Ena, where are you headed today?
惠那今天去了哪裡呀?
The weather seems nice.
因為天氣不錯
I took Chikuwa with me
我帶竹輪稍微走遠一點
and went for a walk in Fujikawa Park.
到富士川公園散步
It's slowly getting warmer lately.
畢竟天氣也開始變暖了
This is perfect for Chikuwa since it never likes cold days.
現在這個季節 對怕冷的竹輪來說正適合呢
I thought so too. I didn't put thick clothes on it,
我也是這麼想的 所以才讓牠穿薄一點出門
but it still felt cold somehow. It's cooped up in the bag.
但牠好像還是會冷 就變成這樣了
It looks like a turtle.
竟然變成烏龜了
Today is the end of your business trip, right?
妳打工的連續出勤 好像是到今天為止吧?
I get two days off after I get off work this afternoon.
今天下午上完班 就可以連休兩天了
Sorry.
抱歉啊
It's my bad
因為我的關係
we can't fix a date for the cherry blossom camping trip.
害賞櫻露營的日期一直喬不攏
Don't feel bad.
別在意啦
Everyone has a job.
畢竟大家都有在打工
It's only right to be considerate.
當然要互相體諒一下啦
What's your plan for today?
那妳今天有什麼安排嗎
Me? I...
我嗎 我啊…
I came a day early to book a camping spot!
提早一天來露營場佔位
While I'm at it, I'm experiencing solo camping.
順便體驗一下單人露營的感覺
Rin is camping alone too.
凜好像也一個人去露營了
I thought the timing was wonderful.
我才想說這是個好時機
This is my first time solo camping.
這可是我第一次自己來露營喔
Aki, you finally muster the courage to try out solo camping.
小明終於也踏上單人露營之路了啊
Stay safe on your way to the campsite.
去露營場的路上要注意安全喔
The whole trip is considering camping until you reach the site.
直到抵達露營場前 都算是露營喔
What is it called when I reach the place?
那到了之後又算什麼啊
See you tomorrow.
那就明天見囉
Sure. See you.
明天見
The sunshine is so cosy.
陽光暖烘烘的
It's making me a bit sleepy.
總覺得好像有點睏了
Almost all the cherry blossom trees are in full bloom.
櫻花差不多都盛開了呢
I did my sketching at the observatory square.
之前已經在展望廣場畫過了
I should try sketching on the green square today.
今天就在草地廣場那邊畫吧
Someone is sleeping here.
有人在睡覺
She is sleeping so soundly.
雖然看起來滿舒服的
Doesn't that hurt her back?
但她的背不會痛嗎
There is a cute creature hiding in the bag!
包包裡居然有一隻可愛的生物
A Pomeranian?
是博美嗎
No, probably a Chihuahua.
不 應該是吉娃娃吧
Nope, that's not the point here.
不對…這不是重點
I have to finish the drawing today.
今天得把圖畫完才行
All right.
很好
I wonder how much I can draw by the evening.
不知道傍晚前可以畫到什麼程度
Just a little bit of sketching.
稍微畫一下就好
I'm... I'm sorry!
對…對不起
Well... You know...
那個 該怎麼說呢
I just thought the dog looked cute when it was asleep...
我只是覺得睡著的狗狗很可愛
-That's why... -I see.
-所以… -原來如此
You're really good at drawing.
妳好會畫畫喔
No... I'm terrible at drawing.
不…我完全不會畫畫
Do you always link this drawing pad to your smartphone?
妳都把這個連在手機上畫圖啊
Do you mind if I give it a try?
我可以畫畫看嗎
Be my guest.
請用
This thing is pretty neat.
這個很好用呢
I've heard how violent a Chihuahua could be.
之前聽說吉娃娃的脾氣都很暴躁
But this little guy here is very tame.
不過這孩子倒是很溫順呢
It's fallen asleep again.
是說牠又睡著了
You're so cute.
太可愛了吧
This thing isn't too bad at all.
這個真的很不錯呢
I want to get a tablet for my drawing,
其實我更想買畫圖用的平板
but I just couldn't spend that much money on one.
但那個很貴 實在下不了手
Yeah. A tablet can be quite expensive.
平板都不便宜呢
"ALARM" Time to get working.
(鬧鐘) 該去打工了啊
Thanks for letting me use that.
謝謝妳借我用那個
Don't mention it.
不會
See you around. Good luck with your drawing.
那我先走囉 畫畫要加油喔
Ena, where are you now?
繪真 妳在哪裡?
I'm at the green square.
我在草地廣場喔
All right.
好喔
Hey there, Ena.
喂 繪真
I'm here.
我來找妳了
You actually came.
妳果然跑來了呢
I have some free time to kill anyway.
因為沒事做 正好很閒嘛
You're still such a great artist.
妳還是這麼會畫畫呢
After you get into high school,
繪真升上高中後
you'll probably join the manga club or the art club.
應該會加入漫研或美術社吧
I don't draw manga.
但我又不畫漫畫
And I don't think I'll fit into the art club.
美術社感覺也不太對
I'd like to join a club that studies illustration.
如果有插畫研究社的話 我可能就會想加入呢
I've never heard of a club like that.
從沒聽說過有什麼插畫研究社啊
So, there isn't one.
果然沒有嗎
I guess I'll just go home after school.
那我應該就會選回家社了吧
I'll work extra hard and save up money to buy myself a drawing tablet.
然後努力打工 存錢買畫圖用的平板
The one with the impressive stylus?
妳是說筆很厲害的那個嗎
Bingo.
就是那個
Why not ask your mum to buy you one?
不如拜託阿姨買給妳吧?
Tell her it's a gift for getting into high school.
就說要當作升學賀禮之類的
I don't think my parents will ever buy me that kind of stuff.
我爸媽應該不會買那種東西給我
After getting into high school,
升上高中後
I should find a hobby or something.
我也來找點事情做吧
There's no need to force yourself into doing anything.
也不用硬逼自己做些什麼吧
But I want to be like you.
但我果然也想像妳一樣
I want to find my passion.
找到自己有興趣的事呢
I bought some snacks. Would you like some?
我有買點心來 妳要吃嗎
Sure.
要
HIGASHIYAMA BROAD AREA AGRICULTURE LINE, FRUIT LINE
(東山廣域農道 水果道路)
Follow the Western Line.
經過西部道路
Then, the Mount Kayagatake Broad Area Agriculture Line.
茅之岳東部廣域農道
After that, the Shosen Green Line
昇仙峽綠色道路
and the Fruit Line.
以及水果道路後
From there, take the Shirai Koshu Line,
再從那邊往白井甲州線
Miyasaka Road,
御八境道
Kanegawa Broad Area Agriculture Line.
金川曾根廣域農道前進
That makes one complete lap around the Kofu Basin.
就會繞甲府盆地一圈
It feels like overlooking the surroundings of a basin.
這條路就像在俯瞰盆地四周一樣
Given it's a complete circle,
圍成了一圈
it kind of reminds me of taking a tour around a volcano.
有種在繞行火山口的感覺
Huh?
咦
I think I've taken this road before.
總覺得之前也走過這條路
Lights are slowly being turned up in the town.
街上慢慢亮起來了
If you keep looking that way,
一直盯著看的話
you'll see even more places lighting up.
亮亮的地方就會變得越來越多喔
Well then,
那麼
let's pull over and take a good look.
我們稍微把車停在這裡 下去看看吧
I remember now.
原來如此
This was the road
當時經過的路
we took that day.
就是這裡啊
There seems to be a light show here at night.
這裡晚上好像還會有燈光秀喔
Really?
這樣啊
Should we come again at night?
那我們晚上要再來看看嗎
If it's not very crowded.
如果沒有很多人的話
Sakura! Take a picture for me!
姊姊 幫我拍照…
That hole is not for you to show your peace sign.
那裡可不是讓妳伸手出來的地方喔
Let me have a look.
我看看…
That makes using the cardboard stand-ins completely pointless!
這樣就沒有 在挖洞看板拍照的意義了啊
Onto the next spot, Nadeshiko.
要去下一個地方囉 撫子
Sakura.
姊姊
Is there a bird pattern on that hill?
那座山上好像有個鳥居的圖案耶
It does look like a bird.
確實是有點像啦
What could it be?
那到底是什麼呀
I wonder.
是什麼呢
KATSUNUMA
(勝沼)
Just today alone,
光是今天一整天
I've already filled the album with cherry blossoms.
相簿就滿滿都是櫻花了
Everything is pink.
一片粉粉的
There is a retro train in the park in front of the station, Rin.
小凜 車站前的公園有復古電車喔
Huh? Is this...
咦 這裡是…
JINROKU CHERRY BLOSSOMS PARK
(站前甚六公園)
The train is so old-school and cute.
這些電車真是復古又可愛呢
Cute?
可愛?
An impression of the train.
模仿表情
What is she doing?
看不懂她在幹嘛
You're really into retro trains lately.
妳最近好像很喜歡這種復古電車呢
After taking a ride on the Abt System Railway in Oi River,
自從上次去大井川搭了ABT式列車後
I just fell in love with these trains.
我就覺得挺不錯的
"TOKOGAWA RAILWAY MUSEUM" I saw this on TV once.
(橫川鐵道博物館) 之前我在電視節目上看到報導
It says there is a museum of retro trains in Gunma.
聽說群馬有一個 收藏復古電車的博物館喔
Really?
真的嗎
If I'm not mistaken...
我記得好像是…
Found it. This is it.
找到了 就是這個
Yokogawa Railway Museum.
橫川鐵道博物館
Show me.
我看看…
"YOKOGAWA RAILWAY MUSEUM" So many retro trains!
(橫川鐵道博物館) 居然有這麼多復古電車嗎
They have an Abt System Train too.
這裡也有展示ABT式列車啊
The location is...
地點是在…
It's about the same distance between here and Hamamatsu.
大約是從這裡到濱松的距離啊
It isn't that far from here.
也不是非常遠
Maybe I should go solo camping in Gunma
下次的單人露營或許可以選在群馬
for my retro-train field study camp.
來趟復古電車考察露營呢
It's better to go camping with everyone.
露營還是盡可能 跟大家一起去比較好
Here you are.
果然在這裡呢
SOUTH IDE CAMPSITE
(南部井出露營場)
The South Ide Campsite is only
從車站步行約50分鐘
a 50-minute walk from the station.
即可抵達南部井出露營場
Plenty of cherry blossoms here too.
這裡開了不少櫻花嘛
I asked Rin about it beforehand,
雖然有事先跟凜打聽過
but there really is a toilet here.
但這邊真的只有一間廁所
There's no water source.
完全沒有可以取水的地方
A rather challenging campsite indeed.
是個難度挺高的露營場呢
But since there's no one here and the site is free to use,
不過這裡不僅沒什麼人 還能免費使用
this is likely a very secret camping spot.
應該是個相當隱密的私房景點吧
Impressive, site hunter Rin Shima. Great job.
不愧是露營場獵人志摩凜 不容小覷
Setting the tent in no time.
迅速紮營
The bed for today is all set.
今天的床鋪搭好了
Well then...
那麼
When you go solo camping,
一個人去露營的時候
it's important to plan a way to kill your free time, Aki.
提前考慮好如何打發時間 是很重要的喔 小明
Rin likes to read. Nadeshiko experiments with her recipes.
凜是看書 撫子是做料理實驗
I can kill my time with...
而我打發時間的方法是…
CINNAMON STICK
(肉桂棒)
Homemade non-alcoholic cocktail!
自製無酒精雞尾酒
The non-alcoholic cocktail we're making today is
今天要製作的無酒精雞尾酒
the Spicy Saratoga Cooler.
是辣味薩拉托加酷樂
It's a cocktail made with ginger ale.
是一種用薑汁汽水 調味而成的雞尾酒
First, in a small pot,
首先在小鍋子裡
add 70cc of water and 60 grams of coarse sugar and heat it.
加入70cc的水和60克的粗糖 並開火加熱
When the water boils,
等水煮沸後
add one portion of lime peel,
加入一顆份量的萊姆皮
half a cinnamon stick,
半根肉桂棒
20 grams of fresh ginger slices,
20克生薑片
and a preferred amount of cloves.
以及適量的丁香
Since we are making spicy Saratoga Cooler,
由於今天要調製的是 辣味薩拉托加酷樂
we'll use Havana chilli powder to replace regular chili to bring out the spiciness.
因此用哈瓦那辣椒粉 取代辣椒帶出辣味
Gently...
輕輕地
If you add too much Havana chilli powder, it'll be extremely spicy.
要是倒錯哈瓦那辣椒粉的量 就會辣得要死
Be very careful.
請務必非常小心
Cook for about three minutes and then turn off the heat.
大約煮三分鐘即可關火
After it has cooled slightly,
等稍微冷卻後
add another 20 grams of fresh ginger slices
再多加20克的生薑片
and let it ferment overnight.
並讓它發酵一晚
But I want to have it right away.
但我馬上就想喝了
So I'll just let it sit for an hour.
這次就放一小時左右吧
Well then...
那麼
While waiting for the syrup to cool, I can pass my time with...
在等待糖漿冷卻的這段期間 打發時間的活動是…
A homemade bracelet made with paracord.
用傘繩自製手環
I've always wanted to try this.
之前我就很想試試這個了呢
"PARACORD" The paracord
(傘繩) 所謂的傘繩
is a high-strength parachute cord with thin strands enclosed in a nylon sheath.
是一種在尼龍管內裝入數條細線的 高強度降落傘用繩
The inner strands can be removed.
而裡面的線可以取出
The strands can be replaced with sewing thread, dental floss, or fishing line.
替換成縫線 牙線 或是釣魚線
Some paracords even contain combustible material inside,
有些傘繩裡面還會放可燃線材
which can be used to start a fire when necessary.
在必要時能拿來生火
It is a piece of outdoor equipment that is more useful than it appears.
是一種比外表看上去還有用的 戶外裝備
Let's try making it right away.
馬上來試做看看
Like so.
把這個像這樣
Then...
再這樣
Tie multiple knots.
接著重複打結
And the line goes through here.
再把繩子穿進洞裡
Burn the open ends.
並用火把尖端加熱
"COBRA KNOT PARACORD BRACELET" The cobra knot paracord bracelet is ready.
(雙色平結傘繩手環) 雙色平結傘繩手環就完成了
This is a lot easier than expected.
比想像中還簡單呢
Wearing it makes me feel like a fashionable camper.
戴起來有種時尚露營者的感覺
Now...
那麼…
My ginger syrup should be ready by now.
我的生薑糖漿應該也差不多好了吧
Put the pre-peeled lime into a glass,
把事先剝好皮的萊姆放進杯子裡
then pour in the ginger syrup and sparkling water.
接著倒入生薑糖漿和氣泡水
The spicy Saratoga Cooler is now ready!
辣味薩拉托加酷樂就完成啦
This spicy aroma is quite appetizing.
這股辛辣的氣味 還挺刺激食慾的呢
Too spicy! It's super spicy!
好辣 超辣的
It seems like I added too much Havana chilli powder,
好像加太多哈瓦那辣椒粉了
but the taste is still quite good.
不過味道還挺不錯的
I should dilute it a little before drinking.
那就調淡一點再喝吧
By the way, I still need to make some side dishes.
對了 還得做點小菜才行
All right. It's done.
很好 完成了
Sauted potatoes with sausages.
炒馬鈴薯和香腸
A simple sauteed dish.
雖然只是簡單炒一下
But it should taste just right.
但這樣應該就很好吃了
Here goes nothing.
我要開動啦
This is awesome!
超讚的
The heat from an alcohol burner is enough for a person's meal.
一個人煮東西吃 光靠酒精燈的火力就足夠了呢
Nice and relaxing.
真悠閒啊
Now I understand why Rin is so passionate about solo-camping.
感覺好像能理解凜 熱衷於單人露營的理由了
That's right. The teacher said,
對了 老師之前說
"I'll prepare the food for our cherry blossom viewing trip tomorrow."
"明天的賞櫻料理就交給我吧"
What is she preparing?
她到底要煮什麼呢?
WINE
(酒)
This is concerning.
總覺得有些不安
I should finish the remaining potatoes.
把剩下的馬鈴薯吃一吃吧
SPINACH CORN
(菠菜玉米粒)
Another simple yet delicious dish.
這道也是純粹而美味呢
Is this a stray from this area?
是附近的流浪貓嗎
Nope!
不行…
This is too much salt for a cat!
這對貓咪來說太鹹了
Unbelievable.
真拿你沒辦法啊
If I'm not mistaken, a cat can have some apple.
我記得蘋果的話 貓咪好像能稍微吃一點
Wait there.
等一下喔
Here you go.
來
You look very clean for a stray.
以流浪貓來說 你還真乾淨呢
That's right.
對了
I found a cat at the campsite.
我在露營場抓到貓咪了
You're having a great time over there.
看來妳玩得挺開心的嘛
I wish you were here too, Inuko.
要是犬子也能一起來就好了
I said I'd be busy today.
就說了我今天還有事嘛
We'll head there tomorrow.
我們明天就會過去了
Enjoy your time alone tonight.
今天晚上妳就好好享受 獨處的時光吧
Okay.
好吧
Come on. Are you leaving already?
怎麼 你要走了嗎
Cats are so unpredictable.
貓還真是善變呢
Whatever.
罷了
I'm headed for the hot spring.
我也去泡溫泉吧
WELCOME TO SOUTH IDE HOT SPRING
(歡迎來到南部井出溫泉)
Arrived at the hot spring.
抵達溫泉
What? You live here?
呃 原來你是這裡的貓嗎
Long ago,
很久很久以前
there lived a girl named Chiaki Ohgaki.
有個叫大垣千明的人
"SOUVENIR" She was brought to a hot spring hotel
(特產區) 被她抓到的貓咪帶到了
by the cat she caught.
溫泉旅館
But the hot spring is simply too comfy.
結果發現水溫實在太舒服
She can feel it melting her.
感覺都要融化了
Not too hot, not too warm.
既不會太熱也不會太溫
Perfectly balanced.
水溫恰到好處呢
The cherry blossoms are still blooming in the courtyard.
庭院裡還開著櫻花
Such a scenic view.
真是風雅呢
Can't agree more.
就是說啊
Huh? Inuko!
呃 犬子?
What are you doing here?
妳為什麼會在這裡啊
NEXT EPISODE: THE SCENERY FROM MEMORY LANE
(下集 回憶中的風景)
WHEN ENJOYING CAMPING, BE SURE TO FOLLOW THE RULES
(享受露營時…) (務必遵守露營場和其設施的規定)
DON'T FORGET TO PUT OUT YOUR CAMPFIRE AND DISPOSE OF YOUR GARBAGE.
(別忘了滅火和帶走垃圾)
TEMPERATURES CAN CHANGE QUICKLY, SO CHECK THE WEATHER FORECAST BEFOREHAND.
(由於氣溫可能會急速變化) (記得事先確認天氣預報)
WEAR WARM CLOTHING IF NECESSARY TO PREVENT COLD.
(必要時穿著保暖衣物防寒)